So we're working with an example of
我们将回收机器人作为讲解示例
a recycling robot and we've already detailed the states and actions.
并详细介绍了状态和动作
In this example, remember that the state
在此示例中 状态对应的是
corresponds to the charge left on the robot's battery.
机器人的电池电量
And there are two potential states, high and low.
有两个潜在状态 很高和很低的电量
As a first step, consider the case of the charge on the battery is high.
首先 考虑电池电量很高的状态
Then, the robot could choose to search, wait, or recharge.
机器人可以选择搜索 等待或重新充电
But actually, recharging doesn't make much sense if the battery is already high,
但如果电量很高 则没必要充电
so we'll say that the only options are to search or wait.
因此唯一的选择是搜索或等待
All right, so if the agent chooses to search,
如果智能体选择搜索
then at the next time step,
在下个时间步
the state could be high or low.
状态可能是很高或很低的电量
Let's say that with 70 percent probability, it stays high.
假设有 70% 的可能性保持高电量
So there's a 30 percent chance the battery switches to low.
因此有 30% 的可能性保持很低的电量
In both cases, we'll say that this decision to search led
在两种情形下 假设决定搜索
to the robot collecting exactly four cans.
会导致机器人刚好收集 4 个易拉罐
And in line with this,
因此
the environment gives the agent a reward of four.
环境向智能体提供 4 个奖励
The other option is to wait.
另一个选项是等待
If the robot has a high battery and then decides to wait, well,
如果机器人的电量很高并决定等待
waiting doesn't use any battery at all and we'll say that then,
等待不消耗任何电量
it's guaranteed that the battery will again be high at the next time step.
可以保证在下个时间步电量还是很高
In this case, we'll suppose that since the robot wasn't out actively searching,
在这种情形下 我们假设因为机器人没有去积极地搜索易拉罐
it's able to collect fewer cans and say it's delivered just one can.
它能够收集的易拉罐数量更少 假设只获得了一个易拉罐
And again in line with this,
因此
the environment gives the agent a reward of one.
环境向智能体提供 1 个奖励
Onto the case where the battery is low.
对于电量很低的状态
Again, the robot has three options.
机器人同样有三个选择
If the battery is low and it chooses to wait for people to bring cans,
如果电量很低 它选择等待有人扔进易拉罐
that doesn't use any battery until the state at the next time step is going to be low.
不消耗任何电量 下个时间步的状态将为低电量
And just like when the robot decided to wait when the battery was high,
和电量很高时机器人决定等待一样
the agent gets a reward of one.
智能体将获得一个奖励
If the robot recharges,
如果机器人重新充电
then it goes back to the docking station and
则回到充电基站
the state of that the next time step is guaranteed to be high.
下个时间步的状态肯定是电量很高
Say it collects no cans along the way and gets a reward of zero.
假设回去的路上没有收集到易拉罐 获得的奖励是 0
And if it searches, well, that's risky.
如果搜索易拉罐 则风险很高
It's possible that it gets away with this and then at the next time step,
有可能这次没有风险 在下个时间步
the battery is still low but not entirely depleted.
电量依然很低 但是没有完全耗尽
But it's probably more likely that the robot depletes its battery,
只是更有可能会耗尽电量
has to be rescued and is carried to a docking station to be charged.
必须需要有人将它放到充电基站上充电
So the charge on its battery at the next time step is high.
因此下个时间步的电量很高
So the robot depletes its battery with 80 percent probability
假设机器人耗尽电量的概率是 80%
and otherwise gets away with that risky action with 20 percent probability.
否则有 20% 的概率躲过这次风险
As for the reward,
对于奖励
if the robot needs to be rescued,
如果机器人需要我们营救它
we want to make sure we're punishing the robot in this case,
则确保对这种情形进行惩罚
so say we don't look at all at the number of cans it was able to
假设我们不管它能够收集的易拉罐总数是多少
collect and we just give the robot a reward of negative three for that.
直接将奖励设为 -3
But if the robot gets away with it,
但是如果机器人没有耗尽电量
he collects four cans and get the reward of four.
它收集了 4 个易拉罐并获得 4 个奖励
This picture completely characterizes one method that
这个图表完全描述了
the environment could use to decide the next state in reward at any point in time.
环境决定在任何时间点的下个状态可以采用的方法
To see this, let's look at a concrete example.
为此 我们来看一个具体示例
Say for instance, the last state was high and the agent decided to search.
例如 上个状态是电量很高 智能体决定搜索
Then, the environment would flip
然后环境将抛掷一个虚拟硬币
a theoretical coin with 70 percent probability of landing heads,
正面朝上的概率是 70%
and if that coin landed heads,
如果硬币正面朝上
the environment would decide that the next state was
环境会判断下个状态是很高的电量
high and the agent would get a reward four.
智能体获得 4 个奖励
Otherwise, if it landed tails,
否则 如果背面朝上
the next state would be low and the reward would be four.
下一个状态将是很低的电量 奖励将为 4
As another example, if the last state was low and the agent decided to search,
再举个例子 如果上个状态是电量很低 智能体决定去搜索易拉罐
the environment would again flip
环境再次抛掷一个虚拟硬币
a theoretical coin now with 80 percent probability of landing heads.
正面朝上的概率是 80%
If it landed heads,
如果正面朝上
the environment would decide the next state was
环境判断下个状态是电量很高
high and the agent would get a reward of negative three.
智能体获得的奖励是 -3
Otherwise, if it landed tails,
否则 如果背面朝上
the next state would be low and the reward would be four.
下个状态是电量很低 奖励是 4
But what's important to emphasize here is
但是要强调的是
how little information the environment uses to make decisions.
环境做出决策所需的信息很少
It doesn't care what situation was presented to the agent
它不关心在 10 个或 100 个甚至 2 个时间步之前
10 or 100 or even two steps prior.
提供给智能体的情形
And it doesn't look at the actions that the agent took prior to the last one.
并且不会查看在上个时间步之前智能体采取的动作
And how well the agent is doing or how much reward it's collected
智能体的表现或收集的奖励数量
has no effect on how the environment chooses to respond to the agent.
不影响环境如何选择对智能体做出响应
Of course, it's possible to design environments that
当然 可以设计与智能体的互动流程
have much more complex procedures for interacting with the agent,
更加复杂的环境
but this is how it's done in reinforcement learning,
但是强化学习就是这么实现的
and you'll see soon for yourself in
当你自己去实现强化学习问题时
your implementations just how powerful this framework is.
就会发现这个框架非常强大